MARKAS FULLER

I am a Cloud System Administrator, I am looking to gain a remote position experience.

Goose Creek, SC markas.fuller@yahoo.com 8435302655

Analytical, highly motivated Cloud System Administrator offering nine years of expertise in supporting, implementing, maintaining, tuning and troubleshooting hardware and software infrastructure related to AWS Cloud, Linux, virtual machines, servers, storage area network and workstation.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cloud System Administrator

OneDataSource - Charleston, SC

October 2019 to Present

Maintaining, monitoring, updating, installing AWS Infrastructure to include: EC2, ELB, VPC, EBS, EFS, Route53, RDS, IAM, SNS, CloudWatch, Security groups, Tags, EC2, RDS Snapshots, Certificate Manager Placement groups and AWS Inspector.

Building scripts with programming scripting languages such as bash and Python.

Daily use of Amazon Linux, Centos 7, Ubuntu 16.04 & 18.04, Windows Server 2012R2 2016 2019

Install, maintain, configure OPENVPN Access Server for VPN services.

Building and maintaining an ELK stack with filebeat.

Jira and Confluence Administration.

Install, maintain, configure Ansible with Linux and Windows Servers.

Github

Linux Administrator/Jr Weblogic Administrator

CACI International Inc - North Charleston, SC

May 2018 to September 2019

Maintaining, monitoring, updating AWS, AWS GOVCloud, EC2, ELB, VPC, Security groups and placement groups.

Install, maintain, and configure VMware ESXi hosts, vCenter Server and VMWare vSphere.

Install, maintain, and configure VMWare RHEL Linux VM servers in a virtual environment in vSphere 6.5.

Installing, configuring, updating Oracle Weblogic in a Linux environment.

Building scripts with programming scripting languages such as bash and Python.

Daily use of Red Hat Linux 7, Centos 7 and Ubuntu 16.04.

Software Integration of CMiC Logistic Construction Software.

Hands on experience with Oracle Database 12c

Hands on experience with configuration management tool Ansible and Vagrant.

Hands on experience with Infrastructure as a code software tool Terraform

Computer System Specialist II

Bennett Aerospace Inc. - Goose Creek, SC

September 2017 to May 2018

Install and operate IT desktops (and equivalent systems and peripherals) in a manner that does not alter the program code or compromise security safeguards;

Recognize a potential security violation, take appropriate action to report the incident as required by regulation, and mitigate any adverse impact;

Provide end user IA support for all operating systems, peripherals, and applications;

Support, monitor, test, and troubleshoot hardware and software IA problems

Apply appropriate access controls;

Implement and monitor IA safeguards for system(s) in accordance with implementation plans and standard operating procedures;

Comply with system termination procedures and incident reporting requirements related to potential security incidents or actual breaches at a desktop level;

Implement online warnings to inform users of access rules for systems;

Implement applicable patches including information assurance IA vulnerability alerts (IAVA), information assurance IA vulnerability bulletins (IAVB), and technical advisories (TA) for desktop operating system(s);

Implement DoD and DoD Component password policy;

Implement specific IA security countermeasures at a desktop level

Desktop Support Technician

Yoh, A Day & Zimmermann Company - Goose Creek, SC

March 2016 to September 2017

Field Service Technician, windows administration, HP desktop and laptop technical support for SPAWAR.

Junior Linux System Administrator

United States Navy - Norfolk, VA

October 2009 to October 2015

Responsibilities

Linux system administration(Red Hat), network system administration(Cisco,IBM)

Accomplishments

Meritorious Award for best employee

Skills Used

Preventive and corrective maintenance
Install and repair computer/networking hardware

Red Hat and Red Hawk Linux

Cisco switches and routers

Cisco operating system

SAN management

VMware

Troubleshooting

- Diagnosing computer system hardware and software related issues
- Troubleshooting experience with network software and hardware
- Keeping professional attitude while troubleshooting under stress

Leadership

• Provided supervision of 4 personnel ensuring preventive and corrective maintenance on computer and networking systems

EDUCATION

Network Systems Managment in Computer Science

Trident Technical College - North Charleston, SC

October 2015 to May 2018

SKILLS

- Linux administration (5 years)
- Network Management (3 years)
- Red Hat Linux (3 years)
- Troubleshooting (9 years)
- vSphere/vMware (2 years)
- Windows 10 (2 years)
- Oracle Weblogic (1 year)
- Scripting languages (2 years)
- AWS Cloud (2 years)
- Ubuntu (3 years)
- Vmware (1 year)
- Git (1 year)
- Python (1 year)
- Terraform (Less than 1 year)
- JavaScript (Less than 1 year)
- MySQL (1 year)
- · CentOS (2 years)
- HTML5 (1 year)

- CSS (1 year)
- Django (Less than 1 year)
- GitHub (1 year)

MILITARY SERVICE

Branch: USN

Service Country: United States

Rank: E-5

October 2009 to October 2015

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

CompTIA A+

March 2016 to March 2019

CompTIA Security+

June 2017 to May 2023

CompTIA Linux+

March 2018 to March 2021

CCENT

April 2018 to April 2021

Cisco Certified Entry Network Technician

LPIC-1

March 2018 to March 2023

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

April 2019 to April 2022

Validation Number VKQGHRPKDJEEQC3H Validate at: http://aws.amazon.com/verification

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

- Linux Administration AWS Python
- Troubleshooting Network Administration Secret Clearance